## Joubert Guimarães de Assis "RedRat"

Software Engineer, DevOps, Cosplayer, Speaker, Open-source community evangelist

#### About

I am eternal trainee of life that works over 10 years ago in technology area, with focus in engineering and architecture of software and with specialization in financial systems and DevOps, moreover speaker around the world, always receiving and sharing the knowledge with wisdom.

## Education

**UNA University Center** - Information Systems Bachelor, 2009 to 2013.

## Professional experience

#### Senior Software Engineer at PicPay - August/2020 to present

- Development of features and fixes in microservices, systems, panels and dashboards of squad.
- Participation in discuss meetings about architecture solutions for projects of squad and unit business.
- Participation in technical and business refinement meetings with the product team.
- Development of spot features and fixes in microservices from other squads and unit business.
- Monitoring of disponibility and performance of microservices from squad.
- Participation in technical interviews and test reviews of new candidates.
- Participation, discuss and talks in meetings of PHP.

Technologies e tools used: Golang, PHP, Laravel, Lumen, Symfony, Docker, Docker compose, Beanstalkd, Minio, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL, Kubernetes, AWS EC2/S3/Kinesis, Bash scripting, New Relic, Swagger, git.

#### Senior Developer at M4U - March/2020 to July/2020

- Analysis, discuss, development, fixes and refactor in applications and microservices with squad according to the demands.
- Management and monitoring applications, microservices and resources of ecosystem under responsibility of squad.
- Documentation of flows and process after development.
- Participation in meets for analysis, discuss and presentation of architecture solutions for ecosystem of microservices and other projects.
- Integration with other members in other squads in chapter for management and operation in legacy systems.

Technologies e tools used: Golang, PHP, Javascript, React, Redux, SASS/SCSS, Docker, NATS, PostgreSQL, Redis, Kubernetes, AWS EC2/VPC/S3/EKS/Kinesis/Lambda, Bash scripting, New Relic, Grafana, Kibana.

#### Senior Software Engineer at Sympla - November/2018 to February/2020

- Analysis, implementation, documentation and management of high availability cluster with Kubernetes.
- Implementation of new development processes for new microservices used in cluster.
- Implementation of new application deploy processes in cluster.
- Creation and implementation of new external integration microservices into new architecture.
- Participation of meeting for architecture decisions into new application and infrastructure architecture.

Technologies e tools used: AWS EC2/VPC/S3/ELB/EFS/Kinesis/Lambda/Route53, Kubernetes, PHP 5.6/7.1/7.3, Symfony, Slim, GraphQL, Docker, Terraform, Bash scripting, Golang, Helm, Kops, Kong, Istio, Calico, Minikube, Openstack.

#### Software Engineer Full at conta. MOBI - January/2017 to November/2018

- Analysis, technical requirements research, development and fixes on microservices managed by team, legacy software and help to other teams if necessary.
- Implementation of security polices suggested by consulting in systems and microservices.
- Participation in projects of structuration of new microservices environment.
- Creation and management of Open-source projects maintained by startup.
- Management of microservices and Amazon Web Services resources and management assistance of DevOps structure.
- Research and implementation of new technologies and tools for management microservices environment.

Technologies e tools used: PHP, MySQL, Sqlite, Symfony, NodeJS, NPM, SASS, Javascript, Css, Linux, Git, Nginx, Scrum, Docker, RabbitMQ, RPC, PHPStorm, XenServer, AWS, Jira, Slack, Electron, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, Rundeck, Oauth2.

#### IT Manager at Vector Internet Business - February/2014 to January/2017

- Management of development, production, software support staffs.
- Elaboration process of new services and resources for existent services.
- Proactivity in presentation innovative solutions for issues using meetings or discussion with staff.
- Management and monitoring all IT infrastructure of company in office and in services provided to clients.
- Development of additional resources and fixes on software's using requirements analysis, coding, tests and publish using version control system.

Technologies e tools used: PHP, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, AWS, Netbeans, UML, DER.

#### Software architect at Mayer Systems - August/2013 to February/2014

- Elaboration, planning, development and implementation of vehicle tracking software and ERP provided from company to clients.
- Management of support process flow for clients and web services, databases, DNS, Linux servers and VoIP systems.

Technologies e tools used: PHP, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, Netbeans, UML, DER.

#### Software architect at IGTI - IT management Institute - February/2013 to August/2013

• Concept, elaboration, planning and implementation of new academic software from institute using technical requirements research, diagrams, mental maps, domain models, proof of concepts and DER.

Technologies e tools used: PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Apache, Netbeans, UML, DER.

#### Programador PHP Júnior na Vector Internet Business - fevereiro de 2014 a janeiro de 2017

- Suporte aos sistemas da empresa, levantamento de requisitos, criação de diagramas da UML, em especial caso de uso e classes.
- Codificação de diagramas da UML em linguagem PHP orientado a objetos e usando a arquitetura MVC e
  jQuery.
- Criação e gestão de banco de dados usado pelos sistemas.
- Elaboração de novas soluções para o cotidiano administrativo e operacional da empresa.
- Gestão dos servidores e das tecnologias agregadas, sendo elas serviços de cloud, web, e-mail, backup, DNS e versionamento de arquivos.
- Treinamento e suporte aos clientes da empresa.

Technologies e tools used: PHP, MySQL, Linux, Subversion, Netbeans, UML.

# Consultor Totvs Microsiga Protheus na Grupo Uniserv União Serviços de Vigilância LTDA - dezembro 2009 a julho de 2011

- Gestão do capital tecnológico e telecomunicações da empresa.
- Elaboração de soluções relacionadas ao cotidiano administrativo.
- Levantamento de requisitos e desenvolvimento de rotinas e customizações para o ERP Microsiga Protheus.
- Gestão dos bancos de dados, treinamento dos novos funcionários em seus respectivos setores.
- Levantamento de relatórios diversos.

Technologies e tools used: Microsiga Protheus, Windows Server, SQL Server, Firewall.

#### Técnico de Suporte na Suprema Informática - abril de 2009 a novembro de 2009

- Manutenção preventiva e corretiva nos computadores das empresas clientes.
- Atendimento remoto e presencial.
- Instalação, implantação, manutenção e gerenciamento de servidores linux, assim como suas rotinas.
- Formulação de soluções para problemas cotidianos enfrentados pelos clientes.

Technologies e tools used: Linux, OpenSUSE, Fedora, Ubuntu, samba, squid, iptables, firewall, ftp, internet gateway, VPN, DNS, pop3, imap, smtp, Amavis, ClamAV, SpamAssasin, virtualização, XenServer, backup, Windows, anti-virus, active directory, LDAP, redes cabeadas, PHP, softwares proprietários.

#### Técnico em informática na Brasol - Brasil Ação Solidária - maio 2008 a fevereiro de 2009

- Manutenção dos computadores, notebooks e utilitários de segurança do escritório.
- Manutenção do servidor de dados do setor de TI.
- Manutenção de computadores a serem doados a escolas como telecentros.

Testes e desenvolvimento do S.O. Linux para uso em telecentros.

Technologies e tools used: Linux, Suite Telecentro, Tucunaré Linux, Windows.

#### Técnico em informática na Fortalnet - setembro de 2007 a janeiro 2008

- Manutenção de software e hardware de computadores plataforma AT e ATX.
- Instalação e manutenção de S.O. FreeBSD.
- Configuração e manutenção de Access Point, Access Routers, Aironet, hacks, Redes Wi-fi e locais.
- Secretariado geral.

#### Professor de informática na Prefeitura Municipal de Santa Isabel - agosto de 2003 a dezembro de 2004

- Formulação e ministração de aulas.
- Comunicação social.
- Manutenção dos computadores e da estrutura de rede da escola.

## Courses and certifications

Udemy - SQL & PostgreSQL for Beginners: Become an SQL Expert

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d321b422-8e97-4667-af44-dc5f20d7abf3

Udemy - Go (Golang): Exploring the Google Programming Language

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d7c3916f-6577-40b8-9830-0282fc3158ab

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 1

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/6C80BAB47C55

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 2

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/9A36463DCC64

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 3

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/F9A9AAB21C68

SymfonyCasts - OOP: Level 4

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/0045F0465C82

SymfonyCasts - Symfony 4 Fundamentals: Services, Config & Environments

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/337CB922C102

SymfonyCasts - Symfony 4 Level 1

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/4ECC5FA2C101

SymfonyCasts - Doctrine & the Database

https://symfonycasts.com/certificates/E2F671CBC103

#### iPED - Polytechnic Institute of Distance Education - AutoCAD 2013

https://www.iped.com.br/certificado?numero=624606

4Linux - Zimbra Collaboration Suite - Total Administration

https://certificados.4linux.com.br

Certificate ID: 4L446300025949 - Code of verification: mGedSL42

PHPrime - PHP Essentials.

Bizmart BHS - 6231 e 6232 - Maintaining and Implementing a Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Database.

**Totvs** - ADVPL I e II, Architecture and Installation, Configurator, DevStudio and customizable reports.

ShapeBlue Brazil - Bootcamp Apache CloudStack On-Line Brasil.

**SENAI** - Microcomputers assembly and maintenance.

**SOS Computers** - Installation and deployment of home networks.

## Contacts and more information

E-mail eu+curriculo@redrat.com.br

Cell phone +55 (31) 98806-9427

LinkedIn public resume - https://br.linkedin.com/in/joubertredrat

Site <a href="https://redrat.com.br">https://redrat.com.br</a>

**GitHub** <a href="https://github.com/joubertredrat">https://github.com/joubertredrat</a>